Office of the Associate Vice-President, Academic fonds
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department
- Academic support departments - correspondence, 1983 - 1998; F-201-3; 4.92 m of textual records; Physical description: includes 16 oversize architectural plans (see sub-sub-series 2 and 11).
  - Animal Care Facility, 1990 - 1993; F-201-3-8; 6 cm of textual records
    Sub-series consists of the Associate Vice-President, Academic's correspondence with, related to, or copied from the Animal Care Facility during the period in which it reported to the AVP Academic (1990-1994). From 1994 on, the Animal Care Facility reported to the VP Research. Activities documented in the correspondence inlude management of the facilities, assessments by the Canadian Council on Animal Care, and development of policy, services and programs. Records include correspondence and reports.
    Animal Care Facility; Canadian Council on Animal Care
    - Animal Care Facility, 1990; F-201-3-8-0-1 (Archival box - standard 201-52)
      Creator's original file classification code: 3.H.
    - Animal Care Facility, 1991; F-201-3-8-0-2 (Archival box - standard 201-52)
    - Animal Care Facility, 1991 - 1992; F-201-3-8-0-3 (Archival box - standard 201-53)
    - Animal Care Facility, 1993; F-201-3-8-0-4 (Archival box - standard 201-53)
  - Archives, 1990 - 1996; F-201-3-9; 7 cm of textual records
    Sub-series consists of the Associate Vice-President, Academic's correspondence with, related to, or copied from the University Archives during the period in which it reported to the AVP Academic (1990-1996). After 1996 the Archives reported to the Dean of Student Services (1996-2000), returned again briefly to the AVP Academic reporting portfolio in 2000-2001, then moved to the AVP Policy, Equlty, Legal (2001- ). Activities documented in the correspondence include departmental budget planning and staffing, search for the University Archivist (1993-1994), policy development, and establishment of the SFU's access and privacy program in 1994 as part of the university's compliance with the provincial Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy Act.
    Archives and Records Management Department
    - Archives, 1990; F-201-3-9-0-1 (Archival box - standard 201-53)
      Creator's original file classification code: 3.I.
    - Archives, 1991; F-201-3-9-0-2 (Archival box - standard 201-53)
    - Archives, 1992; F-201-3-9-0-3 (Archival box - standard 201-53)
    - Archives, 1993; F-201-3-9-0-4 (Archival box - standard 201-53)
    - Archives, 1993 - 1994; F-201-3-9-0-5 (Archival box - standard 201-53)
    - Archives, 1995 - 1996; F-201-3-9-0-6 (Archival box - standard 201-53)
  - Computing Services, 1989 - 1993; F-201-3-10; 10 cm of textual records
    Sub-series consists of the Associate Vice-President, Academic's correspondence with, related to, or copied from Computing Services during the period in which it reported to the AVP Academic (1990-1994). In 1991 Computing Services was reorganized into Academic Computing Services (ACS) and Operations and Technical Support (OTS); from 1994 both of these units shifted their reporting relationship from the AVP to the VP Academic. Activities documented in the correspondence include departmental budget and organizational planning, IT systems, network and infrastructure planning, development of an information management system for the Eastern Indonesian Universities Development Project (EIUDP), and operations of the university's Microcomputer Store. Records includes correspondence, reports, discussion papers, and meeting minutes.
    Eastern Indonesia Universities Development Project; Computing Services
    - Eastern Indonesia University Development Project (EIUDP) - management information system, 1989 - 1991; F-201-3-10-0-1 (Archival box - standard 201-53)
    - Computing Services, 1990; F-201-3-10-0-2 (Archival box - standard 201-53)
      Creator's original file classification code: 3.J.
    - Computing Services, 1991; F-201-3-10-0-3 (Archival box - standard 201-53)
      Creator's original file classification code: 3.K.
    - Computing Services, vol. 1, 1992; F-201-3-10-0-4 (Archival box - standard 201-54)
    - Computing Services, vol. 2, 1992; F-201-3-10-0-5 (Archival box - standard 201-54)
    - Computing Services, vol. 1, 1993; F-201-3-10-0-6 (Archival box - standard 201-54)
    - Computing Services, vol. 2, 1993; F-201-3-10-0-7 (Archival box - standard 201-54)
  - Instructional Media Centre, 1990 - 1993; F-201-3-11; 5 cm of textual records and other material; Physical description: includes 5 oversize architectural plans (see file 2).
    Sub-series consists of the Associate Vice-President, Academic's correspondence with, related to, or copied from the Instructional Media Centre (IMC) during the period in which it reported to the AVP Academic (1990-1994). After 1994, IMC shifted its reporting relationship from the AVP to the VP Academic (1994-2001). but returned in 2001 as part of the newly restructured Learning and Instructional Development Centre (LIDC). Activities documented in the correspondence include departmental budget and organizational planning, and development of services. Records consists predominantly of correspondence, with some reports.
    Learning and Instructional Development Centre
    - Instructional Media Centre, 1990 - 1991; F-201-3-11-0-1 (Archival box - standard 201-54)
    - Instructional Media Centre, 1992; F-201-3-11-0-2 (Archival box - standard 201-54)
    - Instructional Media Centre, 1992; F-201-3-11-0-3
    - Instructional Media Centre, 1993; F-201-3-11-0-4 (Archival box - standard 201-54)
  - Reprographics, 1992 - 1993; F-201-3-12; 1 cm of textual records
    Sub-series consists of the Associate Vice-President, Academic's correspondence with, related to, or copied from Reprographics during the period in which it reported to the AVP Academic (1991-1994). After 1994, Reprographics reported directly to the VP Academic (1994-2000), returned shortly to AVP Academic (2000-2002), then moved to Finance and Auxiliary Services (2002- ). Activities documented in the correspondence include general organizational and budget planning. Records consists predominantly of correspondence, with some reports.
    Reprographics
    - Reprographics, 1992 - 1993; F-201-3-12-0-1 (Archival box - standard 201-56)
  - Student Services, 1985 - 1996; F-201-3-13; 21 cm of textual records
    Sub-series consists of the Associate Vice-President, Academic's correspondence with, related to, or copied from Student Services. Although Student Services did not move to the VP Academic's reporting portfolio until 1994, the AVP Academic maintained a correspondence with the Director and with the various units comprising Student Services, including Athletics and Recreation, Health Services, the Day Care Centre, and Residence and Housing. The AVP Academic's Office also filed here correspondence with or relating to the Simon Fraser Student Society (SFSS). Records consists predominantly of correspondence, with some reports.
    Student Services; Health Services; Athletic and Recreational Services; Simon Fraser University Childcare Society; Residence and Housing Office; Simon Fraser Student Society
    - Student Services - general, 1985 - 1994; F-201-3-13-0-1 (Archival box - standard 201-54)
    - Activity fee, 1986 - 1991; F-201-3-13-0-2 (Archival box - standard 201-55)
    - Canadianization, 1986 - 1992; F-201-3-13-0-3 (Archival box - standard 201-55)
    - Health Services, 1988 - 1994; F-201-3-13-0-4 (Archival box - standard 201-55)
    - Fund-raising, 1989 - 1994; F-201-3-13-0-5 (Archival box - standard 201-55)
    - Student Services - general, 1989 - 1994; F-201-3-13-0-6 (Archival box - standard 201-55)
    - Day Care Centre, 1990 - 1994; F-201-3-13-0-7 (Archival box - standard 201-55)
    - Student Society, 1990 - 1994; F-201-3-13-0-8 (Archival box - standard 201-55)
    - Student Services, vol. 1, 1993 - 1994; F-201-3-13-0-9 (Archival box - standard 201-55)
    - Student Services, vol. 2, 1993 - 1994; F-201-3-13-0-10 (Archival box - standard 201-56)
    - Residences, 1993 - 1994; F-201-3-13-0-11 (Archival box - standard 201-56)
    - Residence - proposal, 1994; F-201-3-13-0-12 (Archival box - standard 201-56)
    - [Athletics], 1995 - 1996; F-201-3-13-0-13 (Archival box - standard 201-56)
    - Student Services, 1995 - 1996; F-201-3-13-0-14 (Archival box - standard 201-56)
- Faculties - correspondence, 1985 - 1992; F-201-4; 15 cm of textual records
  Series consists of the Associate Vice-President, Academic's correspondence with, related to, or copied from university academic faculties and departments, including the Faculties of the Arts, Education, Science, Applied Sciences, Business Administration, Continuing Studies, and Graduate Studies. Activities documented include budget planning, program and project proposals, fees, funding, and downtown campus planning. Records include correspondence, reports, meeting minutes, budgets, proposals, presentations, and brochures and other printed matter.
  The arrangement of the material is based on the original file classification system used by the creator to organize the records. Files are arranged chronologically.
  Faculty of Science; Faculty of Arts and Social Sciences; Faculty of Education; Faculty of Applied Sciences; Continuing Studies; Office of the Dean of Graduate Studies; Beedie School of Business
  No further accruals to the series are expected.
  A file list is available.
  - Faculty of Science, vol. 1, 1985 - 1992; F-201-4-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 201-56)
    Creator's original file classification code: 4.E.
  - Faculty of Science, vol. 2, 1985 - 1992; F-201-4-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 201-56)
  - Faculty of Science, vol. 3, 1985 - 1992; F-201-4-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 201-56)
  - Continuing Studies / Downtown campus, 1986 - 1990; F-201-4-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 201-57)
    Creator's original file classification code: 4.F.
  - Faculty of Education, 1986 - 1990; F-201-4-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 201-57)
    Creator's original file classification code: 4.D.
  - Graduate Studies, 1986 - 1992; F-201-4-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 201-57)
    Creator's original file classification code: 4.G.
  - Faculty of Applied Sciences, 1986 - 1992; F-201-4-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 201-57)
    Creator's original file classification code: 4.A.
  - Faculty of Arts, vol. 1, 1986 - 1992; F-201-4-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 201-57)
    Creator's original file classification code: 6.A.
  - Faculty of Arts, vol. 2, 1986 - 1992; F-201-4-0-0-9 (Archival box - standard 201-57)
    Creator's original file classification code: 4.B.
  - Faculty of Arts, vol. 3, 1986 - 1992; F-201-4-0-0-10 (Archival box - standard 201-57)
  - Faculty of Arts, vol. 4, 1986 - 1992; F-201-4-0-0-11 (Archival box - standard 201-57)
    Creator's original file classification code: 4.B.1.
  - Faculty of Business Administration, 1990 - 1992; F-201-4-0-0-12 (Archival box - standard 201-57)
    Creator's original file classification code: 4.C.
- Senate committee records, 1984 - 1998; F-201-5; 1.32 m of textual records
  Series consists of records relating to the deliberations and activities of various Senate committees. With one exception – sub-series 4, the Senate Committee on Academic Discipline (SCAD) – the Associate Vice-President, Academic either chaired or participated on all of the committees represented by the sub-series. Records include meeting agendas, minutes, and supporting papers; and correspondence, reports, statistics, and notes and working papers.
  The arrangement of the material into sub-sub-series is based on the original file classification system used by the creator to organize the records. Sub-series are generally arranged chronologically. Files are arranged chronologically.
  - Senate Policy Committee on Scholarships, Awards and Bursaries (SPCSAB), 1984 - 1995; F-201-5-1; 21 cm of textual records; Senate Policy Committee on Scholarships, Awards and Bursaries
    The Senate Policy Committee on Scholarships, Awards and Bursaries (SPCSAB) is a standing committee of Senate, established in 1986 when its predecessor – the Senate Committee on Scholarships, Awards and Bursaries (SCSAB) – was reorganized into three distinct committees to deal separately with policy, undergraduate adjudication, and graduate adjudication. The main functions of SPCSAB are to set terms of reference for all university administered award programs and their adjudication; establish budget requests; integrate award programs with recruiting; and establish university policies relating to student funding from non-university sources.
    This sub-series consists of the Associate Vice-President, Academic's working files as a committee member of SPCSAB. It also includes several files relating to SPCSAB's predecessor (SCSAB). Records include agendas, minutes, correspondence, reports, statistics, and notes and working papers.
    - Senate Committee on Scholarships, Awards and Bursaries (SCSAB), 1984 - 1985; F-201-5-1-0-1 (Archival box - standard 201-57)
      Creator's original file classification code: 13.A.8.
    - Senate Committee on Scholarships, Awards and Bursaries (SCSAB), vol. 1, 1986; F-201-5-1-0-2 (Archival box - standard 201-58)
    - Senate Committee on Scholarships, Awards and Bursaries (SCSAB), vol. 2, 1986; F-201-5-1-0-3 (Archival box - standard 201-58)
    - Senate Policy Committee on Scholarships, Awards and Bursaries (SPCSAB), 1990; F-201-5-1-0-4 (Archival box - standard 201-58)
      Creator's original file classification code: 5.E.a.
    - Senate Policy Committee on Scholarships, Awards and Bursaries (SPCSAB), vol. 1, 1992; F-201-5-1-0-5 (Archival box - standard 201-58)
    - Senate Policy Committee on Scholarships, Awards and Bursaries (SPCSAB), vol. 2, 1992; F-201-5-1-0-6 (Archival box - standard 201-58)
    - Senate Policy Committee on Scholarships, Awards and Bursaries (SPCSAB), vol. 1, 1993; F-201-5-1-0-7 (Archival box - standard 201-58)
    - Senate Policy Committee on Scholarships, Awards and Bursaries (SPCSAB), vol. 2, 1993; F-201-5-1-0-8 (Archival box - standard 201-58)
    - Senate Policy Committee on Scholarships, Awards and Bursaries (SPCSAB), vol. 1, 1994; F-201-5-1-0-9 (Archival box - standard 201-59)
      Creator's original file classification code: 4.C.a.
    - Senate Policy Committee on Scholarships, Awards and Bursaries (SPCSAB), vol. 2, 1994; F-201-5-1-0-10 (Archival box - standard 201-59)
    - Senate Policy Committee on Scholarships, Awards and Bursaries (SPCSAB), vol. 1, 1995; F-201-5-1-0-11 (Archival box - standard 201-59)
    - Senate Policy Committee on Scholarships, Awards and Bursaries (SPCSAB), vol. 2, 1995; F-201-5-1-0-12 (Archival box - standard 201-59)
      Creator's original file classification code: 4.B.a.
  - Senate Undergraduate Admissions Board (SUAB), 1985 - 1995; F-201-5-2; 18 cm of textual records; Senate Undergraduate Admissions Board
    The Senate Undergraduate Admissions Board (SUAB) was established as a standing committee of Senate in 1970, replacing its predecessor, the Senate Committee on Undergraduate Admissions and Standing. Its functions were to make recommendations relating to policy on undergraduate admissions, readmissions, standing and credit transfer; and to review applications involving special or extenuating circumstances. SUAB was dissolved by Senate effective January 1, 1996, and its functions transferred to the Senate Committee on Undergraduate Studies (SCUS).
    This sub-series consists of the Associate Vice-President, Academic's working files as a committee member of SUAB. Records include agendas, minutes, correspondence, reports, policies, and briefs.
    - Senate Undergraduate Admissions Board (SUAB), 1985 - 1986; F-201-5-2-0-1 (Archival box - standard 201-59)
      Creator's original file classification code: 13.A.3.
    - Senate Undergraduate Admissions Board (SUAB) - Advanced Placement, 1985 - 1986; F-201-5-2-0-2 (Archival box - standard 201-59)
      Creator's original file classification code: 13.A.2.a.
    - Senate Undergraduate Admissions Board (SUAB), vol. 1, 1990; F-201-5-2-0-3 (Archival box - standard 201-59)
      Creator's original file classification code: 5.C.
    - Senate Undergraduate Admissions Board (SUAB), vol. 2, 1990; F-201-5-2-0-4 (Archival box - standard 201-60)
    - Senate Undergraduate Admissions Board (SUAB), 1991 - 1992; F-201-5-2-0-5 (Archival box - standard 201-60)
    - Senate Undergraduate Admissions Board (SUAB), 1992 - 1993; F-201-5-2-0-6 (Archival box - standard 201-60)
    - Senate Undergraduate Admissions Board (SUAB), vol. 1, 1994; F-201-5-2-0-7 (Archival box - standard 201-60)
    - Senate Undergraduate Admissions Board (SUAB), vol. 2, 1994; F-201-5-2-0-8 (Archival box - standard 201-60)
    - Senate Undergraduate Admissions Board (SUAB), vol. 1, 1995; F-201-5-2-0-9 (Archival box - standard 201-60)
    - Senate Undergraduate Admissions Board (SUAB), vol. 2, 1995; F-201-5-2-0-10 (Archival box - standard 201-60)
  - Senate Committee on Undergraduate Studies (SCUS), 1986 - 1994; F-201-5-3; 33 cm of textual records; Senate Committee on Undergraduate Studies
    The Senate Committee on Undergraduate Studies (SCUS) is a standing committee of Senate. It was established by Senate in 1971 and has been reorganized on several occasions. Through tne 1970s, Senate delegated to SCUS certain responsibilities and authority for approving curriculum and academic program revisions. In 1987, these responsibilities were in turn delegated to the Senate Committee on Academic Planning (SCAP), of which SCUS became a sub-committee. In 2001 Senate restructured its committees, with SCAP becoming the Senate Committee on University Priorities (SCUP) and SCUS restored to a full standing committee reporting directly to Senate. Its main function are to review, make recommendations, and approve academic program and curriculum changes; and recommend to Senate policies relating to grading, examination, standing and continuance, undergraduate admissions, readmissions, and credit transfer, undergraduate course registration and course withdrawal procedures, and the administration of undergraduate student records.
    This sub-series consists of the Associate Vice-President, Academic's working files as Chair of SCUS. Records include agendas, minutes, correspondence, reports, curriculum proposals, course descriptions, calendar revisions, and policies.
    - Senate Committee on Undergraduate Studies (SCUS), 1986; F-201-5-3-0-1 (Archival box - standard 201-61)
      Creator's original file classification code: 13.A.2.
    - Senate Committee on Undergraduate Studies (SCUS), 1990; F-201-5-3-0-2 (Archival box - standard 201-61)
      Creator's original file classification code: 5.B.
    - Senate Committee on Undergraduate Studies (SCUS), vol. 1, 1992; F-201-5-3-0-3 (Archival box - standard 201-61)
    - Senate Committee on Undergraduate Studies (SCUS), vol. 2, 1992; F-201-5-3-0-4 (Archival box - standard 201-61)
    - Senate Committee on Undergraduate Studies (SCUS), vol. 3, 1992; F-201-5-3-0-5 (Archival box - standard 201-61)
    - Senate Committee on Undergraduate Studies (SCUS), vol. 1, 1993; F-201-5-3-0-6 (Archival box - standard 201-61)
    - Senate Committee on Undergraduate Studies (SCUS), vol. 2, 1993; F-201-5-3-0-7 (Archival box - standard 201-61)
    - Senate Committee on Undergraduate Studies (SCUS), vol. 3, 1993; F-201-5-3-0-8 (Archival box - standard 201-62)
    - Senate Committee on Undergraduate Studies (SCUS), vol. 4, 1993; F-201-5-3-0-9 (Archival box - standard 201-62)
    - Senate Committee on Undergraduate Studies (SCUS), vol. 5, 1993; F-201-5-3-0-10 (Archival box - standard 201-62)
    - Senate Committee on Undergraduate Studies (SCUS), vol. 6, 1993; F-201-5-3-0-11 (Archival box - standard 201-62)
    - Senate Committee on Undergraduate Studies (SCUS), vol. 7, 1993; F-201-5-3-0-12 (Archival box - standard 201-62)
    - Senate Committee on Undergraduate Studies (SCUS), vol. 1, 1994; F-201-5-3-0-13 (Archival box - standard 201-62)
    - Senate Committee on Undergraduate Studies (SCUS), vol. 2, 1994; F-201-5-3-0-14 (Archival box - standard 201-62)
    - Senate Committee on Undergraduate Studies (SCUS), vol. 3, 1994; F-201-5-3-0-15 (Archival box - standard 201-63)
    - Senate Committee on Undergraduate Studies (SCUS), vol. 4, 1994; F-201-5-3-0-16 (Archival box - standard 201-63)
    - Senate Committee on Undergraduate Studies (SCUS), vol. 5, 1994; F-201-5-3-0-17 (Archival box - standard 201-63)
    - Senate Committee on Undergraduate Studies (SCUS), vol. 6, 1994; F-201-5-3-0-18 (Archival box - standard 201-63)
  - Senate Committee on Academic Discipline (SCAD), 1990 - 1992; F-201-5-4; 2 cm of textual records
    Sub-series consists of the Associate Vice-President, Academic's correspondence relating to the Senate Committee on Academic Discipline (SCAD) and its proposed revisions to university academic discipline policies. Records consists of correspondence, policies, revisions, and notes.
    Senate Commitee on Academic Discipline
    - Senate Committee on Academic Discipline (SCAD), 1990 - 1992; F-201-5-4-0-1 (Archival box - standard 201-63)
      Creator's original file classification code: 5.H.
  - Senate Committee on Academic Planning (SCAP), 1990 - 1994; F-201-5-5; 33 cm of textual records; Senate Committee on University Priorities
    The Senate Committee on University Priorities (SCUP) was originally instituted in 1971 as the Senate Committee on Academic Planning (SCAP). It replaced the Academic Planning Committee (ACP) previously established under the President's Office and was responsible for coordinating and implementing a system of academic planning at the university. Its functions included identifying priorities in the development of new and emerging programs; coordinating academic planning with allocation of resources; operating the system of external reviews; and reviewing and making recommendations for the establishment and disestablishment of academic departments and research units, centres and institutes. In 2001 Senate restructured its committee organization, and SCAP was renamed the Senate Committee on University Priorities (SCUP). It retained its academic planning functions, but took on additional responsibilities for advising the President on university budget matters.
    This sub-series consists of the Associate Vice-President, Academic's working files as a member of SCAP. Records include agendas, minutes, correspondence, reports, curiculum proposals and authorizations, calendar changes, budget summaries, and external reviews and responses.
    - Senate Committee on Academic Planning (SCAP), vol. 1, 1990; F-201-5-5-0-1 (Archival box - standard 201-63)
      Creator's original file classification code: 5.F.
    - Senate Committee on Academic Planning (SCAP), vol. 1, 1990; F-201-5-5-0-2 (Archival box - standard 201-64)
    - Senate Committee on Academic Planning (SCAP), vol. 2, 1990; F-201-5-5-0-3 (Archival box - standard 201-64)
    - Senate Committee on Academic Planning (SCAP), vol. 1, 1992; F-201-5-5-0-4 (Archival box - standard 201-64)
    - Senate Committee on Academic Planning (SCAP), vol. 2, 1992; F-201-5-5-0-5 (Archival box - standard 201-64)
    - Senate Committee on Academic Planning (SCAP), vol. 1, 1993; F-201-5-5-0-6 (Archival box - standard 201-64)
    - Senate Committee on Academic Planning (SCAP), vol. 2, 1993; F-201-5-5-0-7 (Archival box - standard 201-64)
    - Senate Committee on Academic Planning (SCAP), vol. 3, 1993; F-201-5-5-0-8 (Archival box - standard 201-65)
    - Senate Committee on Academic Planning (SCAP), vol. 4, 1993; F-201-5-5-0-9 (Archival box - standard 201-65)
    - Senate Committee on Academic Planning (SCAP), vol. 5, 1993; F-201-5-5-0-10 (Archival box - standard 201-65)